PROPHET T.B. JOSHUA
THE SCOAN
Thank you. Hallelujah!
PROPHET T.B. JOSHUA
THE SCOAN
So, God has done it.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Thank You, Jesus.
Now you need to ask yourself:
Are you really the person God wants you to be?
Ask yourself.
Am I the person God wants me to be?
That is the question we need to ask. This is what I am going to talk about today.
One can be very rich and yet not what God wants him to be.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
The reward of the person of God is the genuine peace of heart
and the legacy for generations.
Legacy lives for what? - Generations.
Can you see the two things: the genuine peace of heart and the legacy to live for generations.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
One can be a prophet and yet not the person God wants him to be.
One can be a president of a nation, and yet not the person God wants him to be.
One can be the richest person in the world, yet not what God wants him to be.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Think about it.
How can somebody be the richest in the world and yet not what God wants him to be?
Because he or she lacks the genuine peace of heart
and such wealth cannot live for generations.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You can be a prophet or bishop and yet not what God wants you to be.
Hallelujah!
So the question you need to ask yourself:
Are you really the person God wants you to be?
How do we know what God wants us to be?
The answer has been given.
The first step to know our destiny - what God wants you to be - is to get to know God better.
We will talk about that today.
To get to know who? - God better.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
We are not talking of religious conduct and behaviours.
where we are all actually coming from.
Tell your neighbour, "You need to know God better".
You need to get to know God better.
We Christians today claim we know God by confessing faith in the Word
and denying it in action.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You say, "I know God, God is .. .I am a born again Christian".
We confess faith in the Word but deny it in action.
This is why we need to know God better - to discover yourself.
You are what God says you are but you don't know.
You can do what God says you can do but you don't know.
You have what God says you have but you don't know.
If you know you have what God says you have and you can do what God says you can do
oh my God - the sky will be your limit.
You will not compare yourself to others; you will be content.
Confessing faith in the Word but denying it in action.
Trying to believe yet never acting on the Word.
I believe Jesus is Lord. Jesus this, Jesus that.
I'm just telling you your life style.
The kind of Christian you are.
This is why I say you need to know God better.
I'm just telling you, I'm just describing the kind of person you are.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Trying to believe yet never acting on the Word; that is the kind of Christian you are -
sense-knowledge believers.
You have to see in order to believe.
"No, what are you telling me?"
You must see in order to believe.
You have to see in order to believe.
You cannot believe beyond what your senses register.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Let's look at one gentleman in the Bible here.
The Book of John 20:24.
It says:
"Now Thomas, one of the Twelve, was not with the disciples when Jesus came.
So the other disciples told him, 'We have seen the Lord!'
But he said to them, 'Unless I see the nail marks in his hands
and put my finger where the nails were and put my hand into his side, I will not believe.'"
The SCOAN Sunday Service
This is sense-ruled Thomas - a man like us.
You have to see in order to believe; we cannot believe beyond what our senses register -
this is the kind of Christian we are.
Our daily battle is with our senses.
We fight the people we see and our weapon of warfare is not carnal.
Our armour is divine.
We fight the people we see
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Somebody curses you, you believe you want to fight. You fight your sister, your brother.
You preach against your brother.
We react to the things we see.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
The Bible says that we cannot know the things that are freely given to us of the Father
until we are recreated.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
The Book of Luke 10:20 - what does it say?
Don't rejoice because the spirit submits to you;
rejoice because your name is written in the Book of life.
Today we are pastors, prophets, evangelists just because we dream and it comes to pass.
We are pastors, evangelists, prophets just because we prophesy and it comes to pass.
We are pastors, evangelists, bishops just because we pray and things happen.
The Spirit may convict us, speak through us, operate in us
but He cannot make His home in us unless we are recreated.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
There are a lot of pastors, bishops, prophets everywhere - just dream and it comes to pass.
Prophesying - it will rain tomorrow and suddenly it rains.
Ah! You people will come together to build a church for him
because the prophecy has come to pass.
That is your assessment today.
So many of us here become a Christian today because you speak, the results come.
You dream and you say your dream and it comes to pass.
Oh, that makes you a Christian.
What is the way out? That is the question for you and I.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Because you already have to agree with me that you are a sense-knowledge believer.
Tell your neighbour, "You are a sense-knowledge believer".
I can't hear you.
[You are a sense-knowledge believer.]
To know God better is to know your calling and it's to know your spiritual gifts.
What is the way out?
The principal source of finding ourselves recreated is the Bible - there is no substitute for it.
Tell your neighbour:
If there is no substitute for it, how do we get the Bible into our hearts - the Word of God?
Don't forget - the Bible is given by the inspiration of God.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You can read the Bible a hundred times, million times;
as long as you hold grudges, unforgiveness,
as long as you harbour bitterness, envy, jealous, hatred, it makes no meaning.
The Bible is given by inspiration of God. Holy men were carried along by the Spirit.
You can read the Bible a hundred thousand times; as long as you hold grudges,
as long as you harbour unforgiveness, bitterness, envy, jealousy, hatred, it makes no meaning.
It is as if you are reading history. Reading history is reading about events.
That is where your problem comes from.
Tell your neighbour, "This is where my problem comes from".
I can't hear you.
[This is where my problem comes from.]
Face your neighbour, say, "This is our problem".
This is just....
This is your problem.
You take the Bible when you are not happy, when you are very upset, when you are hurt,
when you're facing challenges, situations - your are disturbed.
No! You need a free spirit to read the Bible.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Trust and Obey
For there is no other way
To be happy in Jesus
But to trust and obey
That is just your problem.
You don't have any other problem.
To get the Word of God, you cannot get it.
You have plenty Bibles on your shelf, your library but they are not in your heart
There are here - sense.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
In order to read your Bible effectively, I suggest reading the Bible aloud,
particularly the New Testament.
Say the Scripture to yourself. Say the Word to yourself.
Insert your own name where the message is personal.
Because I want you to be spiritual.
We are only made spiritual by living in the Word and by the Word living in us.
So, I don't know how you walk with the Lord.
The Bible says possessing a spiritual gift is an important part of our walking with the Lord.
Because you can't walk with the Lord. How can you walk with Spirit, when you are not spirit?
How can you walk?
God is Spirit and His worshippers must worship Him in Spirit and truth.
Look, this is the Spirit and I'm here with body.
Is it possible for me to walk with the Spirit?
It is not possible; you have to be spiritual.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Possessing a spiritual gift is an important part of our walking with the Lord.
You have to be spiritual to walk with the Lord.
You have to be spiritual.
You can be a prophet, pastor, bishop and yet not be what God wants you to be.
Message title:
WHAT GOD WANTS US TO BE
You can be a president of a country yet not...
I told you the reward of being the person of God -
the genuine peace of heart, the legacy to live for generations.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
If today is your last day on earth, what do you think can live in you for generations?
What we have now is through controversy, fight, disagreement, "No this one is mine",
debt in the bank - we are rich but so much debt.
Everything we have - enveloped by controversies.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
So please, think about that. It's very very important.
Your calling and your spiritual gift are one.
If you say, "What is my calling?", you are saying, "What is my spiritual gift?" - that is what you are asking.
Hallelujah!
What message are you taking home today?
Am I really the person God wants me to be?
It's very important to discover yourself. What I'm talking about is our destiny.
If I am not operating on my destiny, if I'm not given the spiritual gift to operate,
what I have been going through in the past is enough to send me packing.
Look at the Apostles in the Bible; I look at the trial and temptation they went through
and I now begin to compare myself too.
I see that, "Ah, history will tell about my trial and persecution".
The most persecuted pastor; not only that, there is nothing I have not gone through in this country.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
There is need for you to know your calling.
If you don't know your calling and you are operating, whatever you become,
it does not take these people a second to bring you down.
Your calling is your gift, spiritual gift.
The beginner is not the owner but the finisher.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
PRAYER TIME
Right now, let us submit to the Spirit of God and welcome Him in your heart.
Welcome Him.
Father, we thank You!
I release you from the pain of the past!
Be released from the pain of the past!
Pain of the past is the cause of unforgiveness, bitterness, envy, jealousy, hatred.
Be released, in the name of Jesus!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Anything that does not glorify God, forget about it; put it behind you.
Be released, in the name of Jesus!
Say to yourself, "I am released".
Believe that.
I can't hear you.
[I am released!]
Whatever satan might have used -
satan can use unforgiveness to connect you to himself.
This is weapon.
They are weapons of satan - unforgiveness, bitterness, envy, jealousy, hatred.
These are the weapons satan uses; this is why I say, don't hold offence.
Satan uses offence to connect us to himself.
You say, "Ah, how can satan connect me?" - Yes, through unforgiveness.
You say, "I will not forgive. What this man has done to me is too bad. He cheated me".
Whether you are right or wrong, you are not supposed to hold offence.
That offence, satan uses that to connect us.
That offence is a chain of satan.
You have to. Right now, work on that. Work on your life.
That is when I say, whatever satan might have used -
what are the things satan uses?
Unforgiveness, hatred, envy, jealousy, pain of the past.
He uses those things to connect us to himself.
I can see them being broken!
Tell your neighbour, "I can read my Bible and understand it now".
I can't hear you.
[I can read my Bible and understand it now.]
With unforgiveness, it makes no meaning.
It is as if you are reading History, Literature, Chemistry books.
This is just it - offence.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Listen to me: I'm not praying for you, I'm just telling you what is happening right now.
I can see them being broken!
The chains have been broken!
Agree! Rejoice over that!
Confess this, confess your freedom now.
Chains have been broken!
Chain of affliction has been broken!
Chain of setback has been broken!
Chain of isolation has been broken!
Chain of career failure has been broken!
Open your lips and confess this - freedom!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
In Jesus' name!
The question now: Who is my enemy?
That is the question you need to ask yourself.
Unforgiveness, envy - these are your enemies.
Bitterness, hatred, jealousy, pain towards others - these are your enemies.
If you have nightmare, you wake up, ask yourself, "I harbour unforgiveness; that is why this nightmare.
I harbour pain, hatred, envy; that brother, I have not yet forgiven that brother.
That is why I am having nightmare.
Because this is the chain, this is the connection to satan.
Satan has no route to get you but he uses the route of unforgiveness, envy, jealousy.
Please, talk to yourself.
Thank you very much.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Prayer For The Nations
With Prophet T.B. Joshua
Your nation, whatever you have as a contact point.
God's intervention!
Right now, cover your nation with the Blood of Jesus!
I can't hear you.
Again and again.
In Jesus Christ's name!
Pray for your leader.
Ask God to redeem your leader.
Redeem my leader!
Give them a hearing heart!
God's intervention, in Jesus Christ's name!
I can't hear you.
[Amen!]
Prayer For The Nations
With Prophet T.B. Joshua
Right now, your journey back home.
Now you start a righteous journey, upright journey!
Ask God to strengthen you.
It is not yet over until it is over.
Strengthen me, Lord! I need Your grace.
I need Your grace not to harbour unforgiveness, grudges, bitterness, envy.
Give me Your grace, Lord, not to harbour unforgiveness, grudges, bitterness, envy, jealousy.
In Jesus Christ's name!
I need Your grace to forgive!
Open your lips - I need Your grace to forgive!
Prayer! I need Your grace to forgive!
I need Your grace to forgive and forget, in Jesus Christ's name!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Listen to me.
This is the voice of God:
Now, a new beginning to you!
The way out for you has come!
Take it!
Repeat it!
The way out for me has come, in Jesus' name!
I can't hear you.
[Amen!]
The SCOAN Sunday Service
This coming Friday, Emmanuel TV will be 13 years old!
Ok, since we are not going to see you,
can you rise up and let us wish Emmanuel TV happy birthday!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Happy birthday to you
Happy birthday to who?
[Emmanuel TV!]
The SCOAN Sunday Service
We are going to cut the cake in spirit now.
There is a giant cake here.
Are you with me?
[Yes!]
At the count of who?
[Jesus!]
At the count of Jesus. J-E-S-U-S
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Are sure you cut the cake?
Stretch your hand in the spirit.
At the count of who? - Jesus.
J-E-S-U-S
The SCOAN Sunday Service
What shall we say unto the Lord
All we have to say is thank You Lord
Glory be to the Lord in the highest
Hallelujah
The SCOAN Sunday Service
There is something that makes me
Come into Your presence
My helper
The SCOAN Sunday Service
My Helper oh
My Helper
Thank you!
If not Emmanuel TV, you would have painted me black today.
But I thank God, Emmanuel TV came to rescue me.
Emmanuel TV came to rescue me.
If not Emmanuel TV, what will I say today?
The SCOAN Sunday Service
The story has now become, "Don't tell me, I have seen it, I watched live".
"I have seen it. I watched it live, I'm watching."
So that is Emmanuel TV for you.
So you can imagine the kind of spirit being we are celebrating.
Thank You, Emmanuel TV!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
TT. Monica Asefa 15/04/19
RV: Mel Flowers 20/04/2019